<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alan Papalia</title>
    <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://alanpapalia.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Alan Papalia</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://alanpapalia.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Alan Papalia</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Localization Based Planning for Autonomous Underwater Vehicles with Inter-Vehicle Ranging</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/publication/auv2020-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/publication/auv2020-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In many environments, such as underwater, it can be difficult to get reliable
localization using visual features. This could be due to the environment being highly repetitive or there being a general sparsity of features. In these situations the performance of traditional localization techniques tends to degrade and can give highly incorrect errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key direction in my research is leveraging the use of inter-agent ranging, a
measurement which does not depend on environmental observation, to aid the
multi-robot localization task. However, there is a caveat, the quality of range-based localization varies based on the connectivity and spatial arrangement of the network of agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work I developed a planner which allowed for networks of agents to
efficiently plan trajectories that allowed them to stay in configurations which
were favorable for range-based localization. Read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2010.02861&#34;&gt;
here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-Speed Transmission</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/me371-transmission/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/me371-transmission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the final project in a mechanical design course at the University of
Illinois I worked on a team to design a 3-speed transmission, complete with idle
and reverse gears. In the design of this transmission I used fundamental machine
design calculations to determine the proper gear ratios and gear tooth sizing.
This included hand-calculations and finite element simulations to predict the
gear tooth root stress for every gear pairing. In addition to this I predicted
the bearing load for each bearing supporting each shaft to verify that we were
within the bearing specifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fabricated the transmission with a waterjet and performed testing on a rig which was provided to us. Using this we were able to estimate the mechanical efficiencies of each gear pairing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6-DOF Object Tracking</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/object-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/object-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project was part of a few months I spent at the &lt;a
href=&#34;https://robotics.oregonstate.edu/&#34;&gt; Collaborative Robotics and Intelligent
Systems Institute&lt;/a&gt; of Oregon State University. I was part of an NSF Research
Experience for Undergrads, and my goal was to develop an automated system for
tracking an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The larger goal was to build an entire testbed which researchers could remotely
access and test robotic grasping algorithms on. My part of the project would
allow for quantitative statistics on the grasping experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To approach the problem I developed a Python library that was capable of
interfacing with Intel RGB-D cameras and recording several image streams in
parallel. To then perform object tracking several state-of-the-art pose
estimation techniques were implemented and compared. The comparison showed
improved reliability and performance under occlusion for a &lt;a
href=&#34;https://labicvl.github.io/docs/pubs/Aly_ECCV_2014.pdf&#34;&gt; Latent-Class Hough
Forest framework&lt;/a&gt; developed at the Imperial College London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a grasping experiment the data capture was set to be automated by the
RGB-D cameras and the images were then post-processed by the chosen framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum Fuel Tank</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/fsae-fuel-tank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/fsae-fuel-tank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the Illini Motorsports Formula SAE team I designed and fabricated our aluminum fuel tank. There were several constraints and considerations which guided the design. First and foremost, was driver safety. The fuel tank had to be packaged in such a way that any malfunction could not put the driver at risk. Additional packaging constraints required that the fuel tank had to compactly fit in it&amp;rsquo;s assigned area. In addition, serviceability was a key consideration in that the fuel tank needed to be easily accessed in the event of failures such as fuel pressure drops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond high-level qualitative measurements, fuel tank design also required consideration of the effects of fuel slosh and the weight of the tank. A thin aluminum sheet was selected to reduce weight while still ensuring the tank could be made without leaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fuel slosh has the potential to cause dynamic fuel starvation issues and impact vehicle dynamics. To reduce fuel slosh internal baffling was used. To determine an effective baffling design I set up computational fluid dynamics situations which used inertial loads recorded during real racing events and observed the fuel slosh caused during different baffle designs. The effects of baffling could be measured by the amount of time that fuel was present at the designed outlet and the net kinetic energy of the fuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With both the internal and external geometries designed, I made the fabrication drawings, waterjet all of the sheet parts, hand-bent all sheet metal into it&amp;rsquo;s final shape, profiled the tubes for the filler neck of the tank, and welded the entire assembly. The fuel tank was then leak-tested under pressure to ensure that it would be safe under operating conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Fiber Hybrid-Monocoque Chassis</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/fsae-monocoque/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/fsae-monocoque/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My senior year I led the complete redesign of our team&amp;rsquo;s hybrid monocoque chassis (part spaceframe and part monocoque). The redesign centered around the monocoque section, with substantial changes from the previous year&amp;rsquo;s design required for reasons of structural safety. The redesigned chassis needed to meet several structural baselines as predetermined by the Formula SAE committee. In addition, the previous year had received feedback on poor driver visibility and had several sections which disrupted smooth aerodynamics, limiting downstream aerodynamic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of our monocoque design space was limited by several hard constraints.
As is key with any composite structure, our design had to be a shape which could
be produced on a mold. In addition, the design was limited to composite
materials which were readily available to us. Each section of the
monocoque had to meet all criteria established by the Formula SAE rules
committee. Finally, the monocoque had to be able to withstand the full range of suspension loads it would see during driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond these hard constraints, I set design constraints on driver visibility,
requiring that our shortest driver would be able to see at least 7 feet in front
of the car. With all of these constraints in place, I set about finding a design
which looked to minimize the weight of the monocoque while maintaining smooth
airflow. To maintain smooth airflow I coordinated with our aerodynamics
subsystem to model the airflow off the monocoque under a range of driving
conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;chassis_cad.png&#34; alt=&#34;CAD&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;padding-bottom:80px&#34;&gt;CAD of the final chassis design&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To minimize the weight I coordinated several rounds of mechanical testing of
sandwich panels. These tests were driven by a mechanical properties tool which
used classical laminate theory to predict the properties of a sandwich panel
composite. This tool allowed us to find ideal starting points for the design of
each section of the car and then refine the design through mechanical testing to
derive the true properties of each sandwich panel. As such, we were able to
determine panel designs which met the structural requirements provided while
still finding a minimal areal density of each panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;panel_testing.png&#34; alt=&#34;Panel Testing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;padding-bottom:80px&#34;&gt;Sandwich panel testing to derive material properties&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, design work did not stop here. As previously mentioned, to manufacture
a composite structure we needed some form of mold, but our equipment was not
able to machine a mold of suitable size in-house. This left us the options of
either manufacturing the mold in parts and attempting to align the sections or
outsourcing the machining. Thanks to our wonderful sponsors at &lt;a href =
&#34;https://en.machinetools.camozzi.com/who/ingersoll-machine-tools.kl&#34;&gt; Ingersoll
Machine Tools &lt;/a&gt; we were able to work alongside them to design molds which
could be machined on their large-scale CNC mills while meeting our critical
dimension requirements. This allowed for improved tolerance on the molds,
resulting in a higher quality finished monocoque. To make use of their machines
I had to collaborate with engineers working with our sponsor to ensure that our
molds were machineable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mold_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Molds&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;padding-bottom:80px&#34;&gt;Molds after sponsored machining&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After receiving the molds from our sponsor I worked with members of our
composite subsystem to make carbon-fiber tooling, which would be the final molds
for our monocoque. This was done so that the tools would match the coefficient
of thermal expansion between the tooling and the monocoque. With the carbon
tooling manufactured, our team handled five successive composite layups and cure
cycles in an on-campus autoclave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;tooling_cure.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tooling&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;padding-bottom:80px&#34;&gt;Loading the CFRP tooling for the upper half of the monocoque into an autoclave&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lower_layup.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Layup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;padding-bottom:80px&#34;&gt;Layup of the lower half of the monocoque inside CFRP tooling&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formula Racecar System Design</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/fsae-system-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/fsae-system-architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the 2018-2019 academic year I was team captain for the University of Illinois &lt;a href=&#34;https://motorsports.illinois.edu/&#34;&gt; Illini Motorsports Formula SAE &lt;/a&gt; team. As team captain, I oversaw over 40 mechanical, electrical, and software engineers in the entire design and manufacturing process of our formula-style racecar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This top down design process meant lengthy discussions among team leadership to
establish overarching team goals. This process involved the use of competition point simulators to estimate the perceived competition advantages given by each target, with qualitative arguments given when there were factors which could not be easily simulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these goals I ensured that each subsystem on our team would target projects and design criteria that focused on our team-wide objectives and that our individual design goals represented the team&amp;rsquo;s goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond high-level planning I also focused on the interface between subsystems and ensured that subsystems were taking a holistic view on their project such that design compromises were made between subsystems for the benefit of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Walker</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/me370-walker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/me370-walker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my Mechanical Design I class a group of us designed a ballerina-themed
walker. This included all forms of linkage analysis to determine the appropriate
walker mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;html&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;video width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;240&#34; loop autoplay muted&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;370_video.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our walker exploring the Bardeen Quad as the ballerina pirouettes on top.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed-Integer Model Predictive Control</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/mixed-integer-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/mixed-integer-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of MIT&amp;rsquo;s course 16.413 I worked on a team to derive a model-predictive controller for a simulated quadrotor in a non-convex planning space. I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://scip.zib.de/&#34;&gt; SCIP&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source optimization software in conjunction with simplified quadrotor dynamics model to perform the path-planning subject to obstacle avoidance constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because objects could be placed arbitrarily within the environment, the planning problem was inherently non-convex. For this reason the problem was modeled as a mixed-integer problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alanpapalia/miqcp-planning&#34;&gt; this repo&lt;/a&gt; all of our work is shown in a Jupyter Notebook, along with a brief explanation of some relevant topics in optimization and a derivation of the quadrotor dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steel Spaceframe Jigging</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/fsae-chassis-jig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/fsae-chassis-jig/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To accurately manufacture the steel-tube spaceframe component of our Formula SAE
car I designed and manufactured a jigging system out of steel sheets. The
jigging was designed such that the frame could be assembled inside the jigging,
welded, and then normalized with an oxy-acetylene torch to reduce thermal
stresses and warpage of the final weldment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inter-Mobile-Device Distance Estimation using Network Localization Algorithms for Digital Contact Logging Applications</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/publication/contact-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/publication/contact-tracing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most modern day phones are equipped with hardware that allows for Bluetooth
Low-Energy (BLE) communication with other phones. This can also be used to get a
rough distance between two phones, something which many teams have tried to use
to get contact tracing information. However, this approach has proven
challenging, with the measurements being highly noisy and there being a good
chance of two phones not having a measurement despite being within sensing range
of each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try to combat these challenges, the contact tracing problem can be considered
a sensor network localization problem. This is a long-studied class of
algorithms which attempt to localize members of a network using only pairwise
distance measurements between network members. Modeling contact tracing as a
network localization problem serves two distinct benefits. First, this allows
for multiple measurements to be used to try to estimate the distance between
phones, combatting the effects of noisy data. Secondly, this allows for the
distance between two phones to be estimated even if there is no corresponding
distance measurement between these two devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this collaboration I worked with &lt;a
href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/usc.edu/lillyclark&#34;&gt;Lilly Clark &lt;/a&gt; to test out
a number of sensor network localization approaches for contact tracing. See our
results and read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2007.10162&#34;&gt;
here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-academic&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Academic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt; | 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/media/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.chat/academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
