<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics | Alan Papalia</title>
    <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/tag/robotics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://alanpapalia.github.io/tag/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Robotics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://alanpapalia.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Robotics</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/tag/robotics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>6-DOF Object Tracking</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/object-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/object-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project was part of a few months I spent at the &lt;a
href=&#34;https://robotics.oregonstate.edu/&#34;&gt; Collaborative Robotics and Intelligent
Systems Institute&lt;/a&gt; of Oregon State University. I was part of an NSF Research
Experience for Undergrads, and my goal was to develop an automated system for
tracking an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The larger goal was to build an entire testbed which researchers could remotely
access and test robotic grasping algorithms on. My part of the project would
allow for quantitative statistics on the grasping experiments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To approach the problem I developed a Python library that was capable of
interfacing with Intel RGB-D cameras and recording several image streams in
parallel. To then perform object tracking several state-of-the-art pose
estimation techniques were implemented and compared. The comparison showed
improved reliability and performance under occlusion for a &lt;a
href=&#34;https://labicvl.github.io/docs/pubs/Aly_ECCV_2014.pdf&#34;&gt; Latent-Class Hough
Forest framework&lt;/a&gt; developed at the Imperial College London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a grasping experiment the data capture was set to be automated by the
RGB-D cameras and the images were then post-processed by the chosen framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed-Integer Model Predictive Control</title>
      <link>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/mixed-integer-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alanpapalia.github.io/project/mixed-integer-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of MIT&amp;rsquo;s course 16.413 I worked on a team to derive a model-predictive controller for a simulated quadrotor in a non-convex planning space. I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://scip.zib.de/&#34;&gt; SCIP&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source optimization software in conjunction with simplified quadrotor dynamics model to perform the path-planning subject to obstacle avoidance constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because objects could be placed arbitrarily within the environment, the planning problem was inherently non-convex. For this reason the problem was modeled as a mixed-integer problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alanpapalia/miqcp-planning&#34;&gt; this repo&lt;/a&gt; all of our work is shown in a Jupyter Notebook, along with a brief explanation of some relevant topics in optimization and a derivation of the quadrotor dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
